# 外边没这么做的
Restaurants cook differently than us.
# 既下酒又下饭
It goes well with both wine and rice.
# 榄菜肉丁长寿果
Stir-fry kale borecole with pork and peanuts.
# 你看这花生米 鲜花生剥的
Look at these. They were peeled from fresh peanuts.
# 剥完之后 盐大料花椒粒
Afterwards, parboil the peanuts with salt, star anise, and Sichuan peppercorn
# 煮个十分钟就行了
for about 10 minutes.
# 家里谁都会煮 这也好熟
It's easy to do at home.
# 千万别给他它煮面了
However, don't overcook the peanuts because they will become mushy
# 煮面了就不好吃了
which taste not as good.
# 你再搓一个 小魏你再搓一个
Try it. Wei, you can try it also.
# 别说师父偏心眼儿啊
Don't say your master is biased.
# 你看这菜很简单
This dish is simple.
# 有榄菜 葱姜蒜 小米辣 鸡蛋
kale borecole, spring onion & ginger & garlic, "Xiaomila" Chili pepper, and egg.
# 通脊肉 现在咱开始腌一下
Now, let's marinate the pork.
# 搁点盐  胡椒粉少许
Some salt, and a little bit of pepper.
# 料酒（黄酒）
Chinese cooking wine (or Huangjiu Rice Wine).
# 行了 你看浆浆
Okay, it starts to become sticky.
# 这香油好在哪 它去腥的
The good thing about sesame oil is that it removes bad odors.
# 这一个蛋清就够多的
One egg white is enough.
# 鲜味汁咱增加点香气
A little bit of seasoning sauce.
# 好了 你看这就行了
Done.
# 小魏你看 粘性抓完了
Wei, look at this. After the pork gets sticky,
# 蛋清裹上它也嫩
the egg white will make it even more tender.
# 这香味我在这儿都闻着了
I can smell the fragrance from here.
# 淀粉 好了
Some starch, okay.
# 然后咱再封点油 它就酥了
Finally, let's seal it with some oil, which will make the pork crispy.
# 油是起酥的
Yes, oil makes pork crispy.
# 和匀了
Mix evenly.
# 鸡丁 肉丁 虾 鱼丁都可以
Chicken, pork, shrimp, or even fish all work fine for this dish.
# 中国菜就是举一反三
Master the one to master all is the key for Chinese cooking.
# 一个会了 都会
You learn one and you will learn all.
# 这就行了
Done.
# 肉丁我改为炸
I will instead deep fry the pork.
# 炸的口感上它有层次感
This will enhance the texture.
# 这边是酥的
The pork is crispy,
# 这边吃着也是脆的
while the peanuts are also crunchy.
# 两种不同的脆感 有意思
Two types of texture, very interesting.
# 做饭本身就是一种玩 是一种享受
Cooking is just like playing. It's an enjoyment.
# 齐了 油温也上来了
The oil temperature is coming up.
# 六成油温 油温也别太高了
About 60% is good. Don't go too high.
# 瞬间就金黄色
The pork turns golden immediately.
# 差不多熟了 来一个尝尝
Let's try it.
# 铁手
Iron hand.
# 倍儿酥
So crispy,
# 倍儿香
and tasty.
# 蘸点椒盐都好吃 直接吃就行
You can just eat this with some salt & pepper.
# 什么都不蘸就行
Or even just by itself.
# 咱再回下油
Let's fry it once more.
# 这肉一点腥味没有
No bad odors at all.
# 我待会找一小碗兑点汁儿 这就行了
Now I will make a sauce for this dish.
# 鲜味汁
Seasoning sauce,
# 胡椒粉
pepper,
# 料酒（黄酒）来一点就够
A little bit of Chinese cooking wine (or Huangjiu Rice Wine).
# 酱油 来点糖
Some light soil sauce, and some sugar.
# 很简单 这是烹汁是吧 烹汁
Very simple. This is the cooking sauce.
# 点火
Fire up.
# 葱姜蒜 爆香
Stir fry the spring onion, ginger, and garlic.
# 小米辣也搁进去
Put in the "Xiaomila" Chili pepper in as well.
# 香味出来了
The fragrance is coming out.
# 再加上榄菜这种特殊的香味
Kale borecole also contains a special odor.
# 这个（放多少）根据自己的口味
You can add as much as you want base on your preference.
# 然后花生米放进去
Then, add in the peanuts.
# 火再大点 最大了
Turn up the fire a little more. This is the max.
# 没招了
Can't go any further.
# 这大火啪啪啪一收
Cooking with this high heat,
# 绝对香啊 好
this dish must be good.
# 既下酒又下饭 地道
Goes well with both wine and rice. So authentic.
# 榄菜肉丁长寿果
Stir-fry kale borecole with pork and peanuts.
# 你师父怎么琢磨出这么一个菜啊
I just wonder how did your master come up with this dish (said by Er Bai, the master, himself).
# 要不叫您做鱼香肉丝您不做
Because you won't show us how to make Yuxiang Stir-fry Pork.
# 又学一招小亮 是吧
Liang has learned something new from this dish instead.
# 先给小亮来 一会还上你那儿去吃肉
Give Liang the first bite. Nah I will go to your house for meat later.
# 要不然怎么吃肉啊
I will let you eat first, otherwise you won't give me meat.
# 师父再换一把勺
Let me switch to a new spoon.
# 满满的都是爱
Full of love.
# 好吃吧 好吃
Delicious? So good.
# 给你来二两都不够
I can eat as much as I can.
# 说说吧你们俩人
Opinions you two?
# 师父这菜 榄菜肉丁长寿果
Master, this dish...
# 别介 我得照你
I will hold the camera for you.
# 这菜可以说 北京首创
I first introduced this dish to Beijing.
# 两种不同的脆感
This dish has two types of crunchy texture (one from the pork and the other from the peanuts).
# 榄菜这种回味的香 又学一招
So as the fragrance from the kale borecole.
# 这个菜咱们打包吧
Let's pack this up,
# 回头晚上咱们回去喝啤酒使
and eat it with some beer tonight.
# 这做凉菜也好吃
This dish is good even when it gets cold.
# 这凉菜不这么做 不搁榄菜也行
But if you really want to eat it cold, you don't need the kale corecole then.
# 鲜花生米搁点小米辣
Instead, use some fresh peanuts and "Xiaomila" Chili Pepper.
# 稍微炒一下 用什么炒
And stir fry
# 辣鲜露一烹 那种麻辣口
with spicy "Xian Lu" (Chinese liquid seasoning). This creates a numbing and spicy taste.
# 这小花生米绝了
Those peanuts are so good.
# 这加上肉了 你看吃的满嘴流油
With the meat. Look are the oil dripping from your mouth.
# 今儿亮子来了我高兴啊
I am so happy that Liang is here today.
# 他爱吃肉 专门给他今天现加的肉
He like meat. So I added meat to this dish just for him.
# 原来没有肉 还是师父
The original version doesn't have meat. Thanks master!
# 上桌了咱们 我打包了
Let's serve. I'm going to pack this up.